particle.io 2016-06-17

# Particle | Build your Internet of Things

This privacy policy covers Particle’s collection and treatment of information and data collected when you visit Particle’s Websites or use Particle Services.

#### Section 1. Definitions

1.1 “Particle” means the entity Particle Industries, Inc.

1.2 “Services” means the any and all services and hosted software applications provided by Particle, including but not limited to, the Particle API, the Particle Cloud, Particle’s web IDE, Particle’s Project Share Website, Particle’s website and any other software services offered by Particle.

1.3 “You” means yourself and any entities you represent.

1.4 “Products” means both the physical products produced and sold by Particle, including, for example, the Spark Core, all Shields and accessories, and any kits such as the Maker Kit; and the firmware, provided by Particle, that is programmed onto certain of these physical products.

1.5 “Third Party Products” – includes but is not limited to applications, websites, APIs, software, or hardware that interacts with, uses or connects to any Particle Products or Services.

1.6 “Website(s)” means any web domains owned, operated, branded or co-branded by Spark Labs, Inc. dba Particle Websites include Particle’s “Project Share Website” and community forum.

#### Section 2: How Particle Collects Data

2.1 Particle collects certain data from visitors to Particle Websites in order to continuously improve and enhance our customer’s experiences. This data is collected via the following methods:

2.1.1 Particle, like many other websites, will store session information (often called “Cookies”) in your browser that will help Particle to identify information such as browsing activity, IP addresses and page view order. You do have the option to not use these Cookies; the majority of browsers will have a “help” tool that will help you to prevent Cookies if you want to, but Particle recommends you keep Cookies active as it will provide a better user experience on Particle’s Websites.

2.1.2 When You visit Particle Websites, Particle web servers automatically log typical website analytic data from visitors to our site. This data, which may include details such as browser type, IP addresses, site visit length and referral URL, is used for systems administration, detecting use patterns and generally improving customer experience.

2.1.3 Particle sees and logs non-personally identifiable data when You use Particle Services. Particle logs this data in our system and stores it on Third-Party servers. The only identifiable information this data is connected to will be the account details You supplied when creating Your account.

2.2 Information You provide

2.2.1 When You create an account with Particle, You provide us with data that includes an email address and password. Particle may also give you the option to voluntarily share other data with us that is connected to your account. If any of these details change, You may update your account at any time and modify, correct or delete your account details.

2.2.2 If you are using Particle to connect a Product to the Particle Cloud, You will be required to identify a network and corresponding network password. This information exists only locally, and Particle does not have access to it. When You connect a Product, a specific Product ID will be sent to the Particle Cloud, after which Particle will be able to match a specific device ID to Your account details.

2.2.3 You may choose to contribute and interact on Particle Websites including the Project Share Site and forum Website. You will have the opportunity to choose what information (other than Your user name which is not optional) you would like to make public. You may choose whether to display or give out your contact details and other personally identifiable information on the Websites.

2.2.4 When You actively provide information on Particle Websites, for example when You post, message or interact on the Project Share Site, Particle may retain that data for You for later use. This data is stored on secure third party servers.

2.2.5 You may actively provide payment details when purchasing Products from Particle. Particle uses a third-party secure e-commerce site with a Level 1 PCI compliant payment system, for direct online sales. No employees of Particle have access to the credit card details associated with these purchases.

2.3 Information provided by third parties

2.3.1 At times Particle may collect information from Third-Parties that use our Services or Products. They may provide us with Personal or Anonymous Data that we will use to continue to improve our Services and Products.

#### Section 3: How is data used by Particle?

3.1 The data referenced in this Privacy Policy is primarily used by Particle to improve, troubleshoot and enhance Products, Websites and Services.

3.2 Email addresses and any other information supplied by You may also be used by Particle to respond to emails, phone calls and requests. In addition Particle may use the data that identifies the Product IDs associated with Your account to provide information and technical assistance to You. For example, Your email address and device details may be used to respond to a technical support question that You send to Particle.

3.3 Particle may collect and create anonymous data by excluding personally identifiable information. Particle reserves the right to use Anonymous Data for any purpose and disclose Anonymous Data to third parties at its sole discretion.

#### Section 4: How is data kept secure?

4.1 Particle uses Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption on the APIs (Application Programming Interface) and Websites operated by Particle.

4.2 Particle uses RSA and AES encryption to communicate with Products.

4.3 Data collected by Particle via its Websites and Services is stored on secure third-party servers.

#### Section 5: When is data shared?

5.1 Particle may at some point have a third-party process or analyze some of the data we have collected.

5.2 When appropriate, Particle may share data with entities and persons who are actively doing business with Particle and have entered into a contract with Spark Labs, Inc. dba Particle (such as companies that have created “Powered by Particle” products). A company of this sort will have access to the data generated by individuals who are users of the product created and sold by said company.

5.3 Particle may share aggregated or anonymous data publicly or as described above in section 3.3

5.4 Particle will share personal information with companies, organizations or individuals outside of Particle if we have a good-faith belief that access, use, preservation or disclosure of the information is reasonably necessary to:

5.4.1 Meet any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request.

5.4.2 Enforce applicable Terms of Service, including investigation of potential violations.

5.4.3 Detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues.

5.4.4 Protect against harm to the rights, property or safety of Particle, our users or the public as required or permitted by law.

5.5 If another company acquires Particle or our assets via a merger, acquisition or sale, that company will possess the Personal Data collected by Particle and will assume the rights and obligations regarding your Personal Data as described in this Privacy Policy. In this event Particle will give You prior notification via email or by putting a prominent notice on our site before Your personal data is transferred.

#### Section 6: Additional Information

6.1 Third-Parties may on occasion offer products or services that interact with Particle. Particle will encourage these Third-Parties to follow a similar privacy policy as this one, but you acknowledge and agree that Particle is not responsible for the privacy policies of others.

6.2 Particle will not intentionally gather information from children under the age of 13.

6.3 Particle reserves the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy at any point without prior notification and approval. Continued use of the Websites and Services once these changes are announced will confirm Your approval of and agreement to any and all changes.

6.4 The section headers in this agreement are for structure only.

6.5 If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy you may contact Particle at [hello@particle.io](mailto:hello@particle.io).
